JAMES COLAIRO

21 Rodenhurst Road, Clapham, London, SW4 8AE

Mobile No: 077 3314 9454 Email: jamescolairo37@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an ambitious, hard-working and reliable individual that always strives to achieve excellence and complete objectives proficiently. My previous work experience at Jampend and my other academic achievements have enabled me to work well independently, in a team and have also reinforced my interest in engineering. I am enthusiastic, enjoy learning new skills and working with a diverse range of individuals and tools. I believe that motivation, determination and resilience lead to success.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATION

University of Leicester (2013-2016)

Cardinal Vaughan Memorial School (2011 - 2013)

Mechanical Engineering BEng	Grade	GCE A-Level Subjects	Grade
Year 1	2:1	Mathematics	В
Year 2	2:1	Applied Business	В
Year 3	2:2 (59%)	Applied Business	С

Cardinal Vaughan Memorial School (2006 - 2011)

GCSE Grade A	GCSE Grade B	GCSE Grade C
Mathematics	English Literature	English Language
Religious Studies	Engineering (Double Award)	Engineering (Double Award)
Information, Communication & Technology	Science (Double Award)	Science (Double Award)
	Geography	

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

Dunsin Surveyors, Victoria, London (June 2012)

- Produced a computer system that allowed us to monitor surveys and ensure deadlines were met.
- Provided general telephone support, organised surveyors' timetables and replied to email enquiries efficiently.
- Impressed Company director and invited to stay on as a summer intern.
- These tasks helped develop my confidence and organisational abilities whilst obtaining transferable skills.

Café Pronto/ Masters Catering, Waterloo, London (Part-Time Summer Placement, 2011-present)

- Generated higher customer satisfaction and sales by promoting daily specials.
- Served customers, placed orders and operated the till under pressure and at busy times.
- Developed good presentation, communication and interpersonal skills.

February London Ltd, West End, London (June 2010)

- Assisted with the design of exhibition panels and conducted market research.
- Learned the importance of working as part of a team.

VOLUNTARY EXPERIENCE

July 2016 - August 2016

• Undertook a six week voluntary work experience with Simpson Marine in Singapore, where I installed a sail, fixed an airconditioning unit and assisted in fault finding on a boat engine amongst various other roles.

August 2015

• During my work experience at TFL, I shadowed a senior member of staff. I learnt the importance of organisation, teamwork and co-operation and how these are crucial for the smooth and efficient running of a corporation.

September 2013- June 2014

- Involved in the Engineering Society at the University of Leicester, where I developed team-building and social skills.
- Coach and player for the Engineering Society football team which helped enhance my managerial and planning abilities. July 2013
- Volunteered for 2 weeks in Santiago de Compostela, Spain, welcoming pilgrims after walking their Camino.
- Helped with general enquires and co-ordinated the "left luggage" department.
- This experience developed my interpersonal and Spanish speaking skills.

July, August 2012 (Jampend Investments Ltd Property Development)

- · Assisted in the development of flat conversions in Clapham, London SW4.
- Learned new designing and planning skills whilst listening to different opinions and obtaining exposure to building site management.

ACADEMIC ENGINEERING ACHIEVEMENTS (UNIVERSITY OF LEICESTER 2013-2014)

1-Week Apprenticeship Course

- Working as part of a team I dismantled and reassembled a car engine.
- Connected wiring from a power supply to an electrical socket. Tested the socket using Voltage Detector Probes to ensure it operated successfully.
- Soldered electrical components (e.g. LED and Integrated Circuit etc.) and wires to a PCB. Once completed I performed a fault finding task to simulate a real life problem.
- Having accomplished these tasks I developed a better understanding of how the complicated car engine mechanics work and their significance, whilst also establishing how to manipulate electrical systems and components.

Formula Student

Working alongside Final Year Engineering Undergraduates I participated in Formula Student as part of an extra-curricular
activity. I presented ideas that I felt would help improve the performance of the car whilst learning the attention to detail
required to succeed.

ENGINEERING/DT RELATED ACHIEVEMENTS (CARDINAL VAUGHAN MEMORIAL SCHOOL 2006-2011)

F1 in Schools:

• Assisted in the co-ordination, design and construction of a model car, which was entered into the 'F1 in Schools' National Competition. Although we did not win, the overall experience was invaluable and I achieved a sense of accomplishment.

Radio project:

• Successfully designed and crafted a radio using electrical components and CAD CAM. Participating in this project increased my knowledge of how to operate CAD CAM and soldering electrical components.

Model Bridge:

• As a pair, we designed and engineered a model bridge strong enough to hold a 5kg weight, using MDF. I developed various transferable skills to deal with other load-bearing structures.

Toolbox:

• Designed and produced a metal toolbox, which involved annealing, soldering, bending, tapping and threading. This task developed my understanding of how metals behave under different conditions and how to manipulate them.

Imperial College London Workshop:

• Attended a summer holiday workshop at Imperial College London, where one of the tasks involved designing and creating a motorised robot. As a team, we were provided with metal strips, nuts and bolts and a motor mechanism. The aim was to manoeuvre the robot up a small ramp. This experience enhanced and strengthened my interest in engineering.

ACHIEVEMENTS AND OTHER SKILLS

- Working as a volunteer in 2013 inspired me to walk the Camino Francés to Santiago de Compostela (Spain). In the summer
 of 2014 my brother and I walked 208km over 9 days as pilgrims from Ponferrada to Santiago. This was an incredible
 experience where I achieved a sense of accomplishment and managed to complete a life goal. My intention is to walk
 another Camino, but hopefully from a further distance.
- Computer literate and have a proficient use of Microsoft Office package as well as other CAD programs (OrCAD, PSpice, AutoCAD, SolidWorks, LabView, Matlab).
- Obtained a Football Association Level 1 Coaching Licence in August 2013.
- During my second year at university, I used my coaching licence to manage the Engineering Football Team, which saw us reach the semi-finals of the league.
- In September 2012 I was appointed Senior Prefect at the Cardinal Vaughan Memorial School. During this time I coordinated and ensured the smooth and successful operation of Open Evenings and other school social events.
- Member of the Cardinal Vaughan Football Team during the academic years of 2009-2012. This participation developed my
 confidence, organisational skills and reinforced my determination to succeed in order to have a positive impact alongside my
 peers.
- I completed a lesson in flying a light aircraft. I thoroughly enjoyed the experience and it enhanced my interest in engineering and how engineers can change the future.
- ABRSM Saxophone Grade 1-5 achieving Merit (September 2006- June 2009)
- Valid Driving Licence

REFERENCES - AVAILABLE ON REQUEST